Okay. So, um I told you that you could
use CSS selectors to target specific
things. Well, you can also use that to
grab specific elements off the page. Um
the way you do that is um you use query
selector or query selector all. So,
let's say I want to target this H1 tag.
In order to do that, I would say
document.get get
uh sorry doquery selector
and in there it takes a way of selecting
something. So I could do div h1. So what
I'm saying is go find a div that has an
h1 immediately inside of it. The way
query selector works is it finds the
first match and returns it as an
element. Um, so I could say let my
elements equal document.query selector.
Um, and then I could say myelementstyle
dot
um color is and then I'll just set it
equal to
that color. So, I'm going to change it
from aqua
or sorry, I'm going to change it from
white to gray, which we'll see if that
actually even shows up. Okay, so I click
change the colors and this div changed
color slightly. Um, and you can see as
compared to this um div that was not
affected, but you'll notice both of
these are H1 tags inside of the div.
When I click change the color, it only
changed the first one. And that is
because query selector just finds the
first match based on the selector you
gave it. So it just finds the first div
that has an H1 tag as the immediate
child and that is this H1 tag. This H1
tag according to styling um right here
is also found. So if you want to grab
both of them, instead of sayingquery
selector, you can say query selector all
and that will grab all of the H1 tags
that are immediate children of divs.
In that case, what it returns is an
array. So you can say my l
and you can loop through it. Um I've
been using for of loops recently, but
I'm going to switch this to be a for
each loop. The way you do that is you
say my lfor
and it says and it takes a function and
it applies it to each element in the
list. So I'm going to say take an
element out of the list and go into the
element access its style and set its
color equal to that color.
Now when we come over here and I click
change the colors, it grabs both H1 tags
inside of the div and changes them. But
it doesn't change this first H1 tag
because the selector did not target it.
And that is how you can use uh query
select selector and query selector all
to use CSS selectors to target specific
HTML elements.